Record Industry Publicity Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
Record industry publicity collection 1937-1979 1946-1955
21.75 linear feet (41 boxes and 8 oversize folders)
Recorded Sound Reference Center, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Press releases, record catalogs, radio program scripts, promotional posters, monthly publications about new record releases, and other materials advertising sound recordings.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
Organizations
American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers.; Broadcast Music, inc.; Capitol Records, Inc.; Columbia Recording Corporation.; Columbia Records, Inc.; Decca Records (Firm); MGM Records.; National Broadcasting Company.; Peters International, Inc.; Radio Corporation of America. RCA Victor Division.; RCA Manufacturing Company, inc.
Subjects
Mail-order sound recording industry.; Music--Discography--Catalogs.; Sound recording industry.; Sound recordings--Catalogs.
Form/Genre
Fliers (Printed matter); Mail order catalogs.; Posters.; Press releases.; Promotional materials.; Trade catalogs.
Administrative Information
Collection Acquisition
The collection was transferred from the Library of Congress Music Division to the Recorded Sound Section at an unspecified time.
Provenance
The Record Industry Publicity Collection is formed of promotional materials that were mailed from record label publicity departments to the Library of Congress Music Division during 1940s through the 1970s. The Music Division later transferred the materials to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, where it was processed as a collection.
Additions
No further additions to the collection are expected.
Access Restrictions
The Record Industry Publicity Collection is open for research. Advance notice is required; contact a reference librarian in the Recorded Sound Reference Center, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress, Washington, DC, 20540-4690; (202) 707- 7833.
Scope and Content
The collection includes press releases, disc catalogs, scripts from radio programs, monthly publications about new record releases, and promotional posters. The materials were originally created to promote recordings issued by labels such as Capitol, Columbia, Decca, and RCA Victor; broadcasters such as NBC; and performance rights organizations such as ASCAP and BMI.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged in 14 series:
Series 1: ASCAP (American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers)
Series 2: BMI (Broadcast Music, Inc.)
Series 3: Capitol Records
Series 4: Columbia Records
Series 5: MGM
Series 6: NBC (National Broadcasting Company)
Series 7: Peters International
Series 8: Decca Records
Series 9: Epic Records
Series 10: RCA Victor Records
Series 11: RCA Victor Argentina
Series 12: Independent Record Labels
Series 13: Radio Companies
Series 14: Concert and Festival Programs and Announcements
http://lccn.loc.gov/2010616902
Container List
- Series 1. ASCAP (American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers) Radio Program Service, 1942, .5 linear feet (Box-folder 1/1-4)
  The series consists of scripts from ASCAP's Radio Program Service. Programs represented are "Music Just for You," "Music...As You Like It," and "You Shall Have Music."
  Materials are arranged chronologically.
- Series 2. BMI (Broadcast Music, Inc.), 1946-1952, 5 linear feet
  Publicity material for Broadcast Music, Inc., including individual series publications entitled Bulletin and Concert Music. Concert Music includes Concert Pin-up Sheet, Today in Music, and Your Concert Hall. Also includes script sheets for the BMI-sponsored radio shows Inside Story, Milestones, Spotlight on a Star, and According to the Record.
  Materials are arranged according to publication type, starting with publicity material and followed by scripts for radio series. Arranged chronologically within each publication.
  - Bulletin
    - 1946 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Concert Music
    - 1951 (Box-folder 2/4-5)
    - 1952, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 2-3, Box 2, Box 3)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 3/2-3)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Inside Story
    - Scripts 1-48, 1947-1948, Lacking scripts 13-24. (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Scripts 49-84, 1948 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Scripts 85-120, 1948 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Scripts 121-144, 1948 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Inside Story, 2nd series
    - Scripts 145-180, 1949 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Scripts 181-204, 217-228, 1949, Lacking scripts 205-216. (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Scripts 229-264, 1949 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Scripts 265-300, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Scripts 301-336, 1950 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Scripts 337-372, 1950 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Scripts 373-408, 1950 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Scripts 409-456, 1951 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Milestones
    - 1954 (Box-folder 5/4-5)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 6/1-2)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Pin-up sheets, undated (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Record Bulletin, 1950, 1952 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Spotlight on a Star, 2nd series
    - Nos. 37-48, 73-108, 1950 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Nos. 109-192, 1950 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Nos. 193-288, [1950?]-1951 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Nos. 289-360, 1951 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Nos. 361-432, 1952 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Miscellaneous published memos and newsletters, 1952, 1954, and undated, Material includes It's Touchdown Time, BMI Music Memo, BMI Newsletter, and Vital Changes. (Box-folder 7/3)
  - BMI Presents According to the Record
    - 1948 (Box-folder 8/1-4)
    - 1949, (2 folders) (Box 8-9, Box 8, Box 9)
    - 1950, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 9-10, Box 9, Box 10)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 10/2-5)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 11/1-2)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 11/3-5)
- Series 3. Capitol Records, 1944-1959, 2 linear feet
  The series includes publicity material for Capitol Records, including individual series publications entitled From Capitol Records Information Bureau, Classical Programming Service, and Platter Patter from the Corner of Sunset and Vine. Further includes a numbered series of cards featuring new releases (which are listed below as New Capitol Records pamphlets and Capitol new releases cards), as well as a series of indexed Reviewer's Reference Cards (which are numbered by release) and ephemera.
  Materials are arranged according to publication type, starting with publicity material and followed by new release cards and pamphlets. Arranged chronologically within each publication.
  - Capitol Records Information Bureau
    - 1947 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - 1949-1950, and undated (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Classical Programming Service
    - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Platter Patter from the Corner of Sunset and Vine, 1950 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - New Capitol Records pamphlets
    - 1944, and undated (Box-folder 13/1)
    - 1945-1946 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - 1947 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Capitol new releases cards
    - 1950-1951 (Box-folder 13/6)
    - 1951-1954 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Reviewers' Reference Card
    - Nos. 71-80, 1947 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Nos. 81-90, 1947 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Nos. 91-96, 1947 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Nos. 98-103, 1948 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Nos. 104-110, 1948 (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Nos. 111-117, 1948 (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Nos. 118-120, 142-144, 1948 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Nos. 145-150, circa 1948 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Nos. 151-156, circa 1949 (Box-folder 15/2)
  - Capitol Records Artist Bio Filecards, 1948 (Box-folder 15/3)
  - Capitol Records releases, 1950 (Box-folder 15/4)
  - The Gazette, 1949 (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Capitol Telefunken Classical Release, 1949 (Box-folder 15/6)
  - Tennessee Ernie's Anticipation Blues, 1949 (Box-folder 15/7)
  - Latest Additions to Capitol's Catalog, 1949, and undated (Box-folder 15/8)
  - Miscellaneous press releases and publicity, 1945-1953, and undated (Box-folder 15/9)
  - Capitol Records ephemera
    - 1940s, and undated (Box-folder 15/10)
    - 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 15/11)
  - Full Dimensional Sound liner notes, 1955 (Box-folder OSC 1/1)
- Series 4. Columbia Records, 1943-1957, 4.5 linear feet
  Series 4 includes publicity material and press department releases for Columbia Records, including individual series publications entitled News about Columbia Records, Speaking of Records, Columbia Records Biographical Service, Columbia LP Masterworks News, and News about Columbia Popular Records. The series also contains monthly supplements to the Columbia Numerical Catalog.
  Materials are arranged according to publication type, starting with publicity material and followed by the numerical catalog. Arranged chronologically within each publication.
  - News about Columbia Records
    - 1949 (Box-folder 16/1-2)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 16/3-4)
    - 1951, and undated (Box-folder 16/5)
  - News from Columbia Records
    - 1943, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 17/2)
    - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Speaking of Records
    - 1949-1950 (Box-folder 17/4)
    - 1951-1953 (Box-folder 17/5)
    - 1954, and undated (Box-folder 17/6)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Columbia Records biographical service
    - 1950-1954 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - undated (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Dateline Columbia Masterworks, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 18/5)
  - News about Columbia Masterworks Records, 1955 (Box-folder 18/6)
  - Columbia LP Masterworks News
    - 1952 (Box-folder 18/7)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 18/9)
  - Columbia Masterworks, 1947, and undated (Box-folder 18/10)
  - News of the Stars on Columbia Masterworks Records, 1947 (Box-folder 18/11)
  - News: Columbia Masterworks, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 18/12)
  - News about Columbia LP Records
    - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 19/2)
    - 1951, and undated (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Columbia Records News
    - 1945 (Box-folder 19/4)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 19/5)
    - 1947, and undated (Box-folder 19/6)
  - News about Columbia Popular Records
    - 1952 (Box-folder 19/7)
    - 1953-1954 (Box-folder 19/8-9)
    - 1955-1957 (Box-folder 19/10-11)
  - New Releases: Columbia Records, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Columbia Records Publicity Bulletin, 1947 (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Columbia Records Children's News, 1952, 1955, and undated (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Columbia Popular Records, 1945 (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Columbia Okeh Popular Records, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/5)
  - News of the Stars on Columbia Records, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Advance News from Columbia Records, 1954 (Box-folder 20/7)
  - News: Columbia Records Trade, 1956 (Box-folder 20/8)
  - Coming Up!, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 20/9)
  - 5th Anniversary Special LP News from Columbia Records, Inc., 1953 (Box-folder 20/10)
  - Leonard Bernstein, 1956 (Box-folder 20/11)
  - The Philadelphia Orchestra, "The World's Greatest Orchestra," 1945/1955, 10th Anniversary on Columbia Records, 1955 (Box-folder 20/12)
  - Dateline Broadway, 1956 (Box-folder 20/13)
  - Dateline Christmas, 1956 (Box-folder 20/14)
  - Dateline Columbia Pops, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 20/15)
  - Columbia press department releases
    - 1953-1954 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - 1955-1956 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - Publicity releases
    - 1949-1956 (Box-folder 21/3)
    - undated (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Columbia Recording Corporation publicity material
    - 1944-1945, and undated (Box-folder 21/5)
    - 1945-1947 (Box-folder 21/6)
  - Miscellaneous Columbia releases, 1943-1945, and 1956 (Box-folder 21/7)
  - Miscellaneous promotional material, 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 21/8)
  - Ephemera, 1951, 1953, and undated (Box-folder 21/9)
  - Assorted pamphlets and catalogs, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 21/10)
  - Numerical catalog, replaced sheets, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 22/1)
  - Numerical catalog
    - 1948, Each folder represents a monthly installment from May through August. (Box-folder 22/2-5)
    - 1949, Each folder represents a monthly installment from June through December. (Box-folder 22/6-12)
    - 1950, (5 folders); (3 folders) (Box 22-23, Box 22, Box 23)
      Each folder represents a monthly installment including January, June through September, and October through December.
    - 1951, Each folder represents a monthly installment from January through April, and August through December. (Box-folder 23/4-13)
    - 1952, Each folder represents a monthly installment for the entire year. (Box-folder 24/1-12)
    - 1953, Each folder represents a monthly installment from January through June. (Box-folder 24/13-18)
  - Numerical catalog supplement, 1953 (Box-folder 24/19)
- Series 5. MGM Records, 1948-1955, 1.5 linear feet
  Series 5 contains press releases, including individual titles such as Disk Data, New Releases, and News from MGM Records.
  Arranged chronologically within each publication.
  - Disk Data
    - 1949 (Box-folder 25/1-2)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 25/3-4)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 25/5-6)
    - 1952 (Box-folder 26/1-2)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 26/3)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 26/4)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 26/5)
  - New Releases
    - 1949 (Box-folder 26/6)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 26/7)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 26/8)
    - 1952 (Box-folder 26/9)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 27/1)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 27/2)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 27/3)
    - undated (Box-folder 27/4)
  - News from MGM Records
    - 1948 (Box-folder 27/5)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 27/6)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 27/7)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 27/8)
    - undated (Box-folder 27/9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1949, 1953 (Box-folder 27/10)
- Series 6. NBC (National Broadcasting Company), 1944-1953, .5 linear feet
  Series includes publicity material, including individual titles such as Music News from NBC, NBC Music Round-up, and University of the Air.
  - Music News from NBC
    - 1944-1949 (Box-folder 28/1)
    - 1950-1953 (Box-folder 28/2)
  - NBC Music Round-up, 1945-1951 (Box-folder 28/3)
  - University of the Air, 1945 (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Information...from NBC Public Affairs and Education, 1950 (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Television News, 1945 and 1953 (Box-folder 28/6)
- Series 7. Peters International, 1969-1979, 1.5 linear feet
  The series consists of promotional correspondence and various catalogs, including individually entitled series such as Grapevine, Peters International Illustrated Catalog, and New Releases.
  Materials are arranged according to publication type, starting with promotional correspondence and followed by catalogs. Arranged chronologically within each publication.
  - Promotional correspondence, 1972, and undated (Box-folder 29/1)
  - Arion, 1976 (Box-folder 29/2)
  - Catalogs of recordings grouped by country or region, undated (Box-folder 29/3)
    Separate catalogs for African, East Indies, Indian, Latin American, and Middle Eastern recordings. In addition, there is one catalog from the Philips/Fontana group of world music labels arranged alphabetically by country.
  - Classical Catalog - Checklist, 1974 (Box-folder 29/4)
  - Complete Catalog Listing, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 29/5)
  - Dealers Confidential Information, 1969 (Box-folder 29/6)
  - Grapevine
    - 1970-1972 (Box-folder 29/7)
    - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 29/8)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 29/9)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 29/10)
    - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 29/11)
    - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 30/1)
  - Illustrated Catalog/Imported Classical, 1970s (Box-folder 30/2)
  - Illustrated Catalog/Imported Jazz-Pop, Blues-Rock, 1976 (Box-folder 30/3)
  - Illustrated Catalog
    - circa 1960s and 1976, Includes Imported French and Imported German catalogs. (Box-folder 30/4)
    - 1976-1977, and undated, Includes Indian, Israeli, Italian, and Mid-East catalogs. (Box-folder 30/5)
  - Illustrated Catalog/Tapes, 1973 (Box-folder 30/6)
  - New Releases
    - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 30/7)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 31/1)
    - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 31/2)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 31/3)
    - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 31/4)
  - New Releases, Numerical, 1976 (Box-folder 31/5)
  - Numerical Catalog Listings, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 31/6)
  - Records & Tapes from around the World
    - 1978 (Box-folder 31/7)
    - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 31/8)
  - Religious Recordings, circa 1970s (Box-folder 31/9)
- Series 8. Decca Records, 1939-1979, 1 linear foot
  Series 8 includes a numbered series of cards featuring new releases for Decca Records and subsidiary labels, such as Commodore and the British Decca company, numbered by release; also includes press releases such as the individually titled series From Decca Records; further includes a series of pamphlets containing notes for album sets issued by Decca; press releases for Decca Distributing Corporation; and ephemera, including advertisements and catalogs.
  Materials are arranged according to publication type, starting with new release cards and pamphlets, followed by press releases and catalogs. Arranged chronologically within each publication.
  - New record releases
    - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 32/1)
    - 1944 (Box-folder 32/2)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 32/3)
    - 1946-1948 (Box-folder 32/4-5)
  - Catalog release cards, undated (Box-folder 32/6)
  - Full Frequency Range Records Imported from England, 1947-1948, and undated (Box-folder 32/7)
  - Commodore Records (released through Decca distributing corporation), 1947 (Box-folder 32/8)
  - Ephemera, 1943-1947, and undated (Box-folder 32/9)
  - From Decca Records
    - 1944-1945, and undated (Box-folder 33/1)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Album series, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 33/3)
  - Best-selling Decca popular records, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Decca Brunswick News Letter, 1944 (Box-folder 33/5)
  - Decca distributing corporation, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 33/6)
  - Assorted record player equipment advertisements, 1939, and undated (Box-folder 33/7)
  - Season's Greetings, undated (Box-folder 33/8)
  - New Decca Records, 1940 (Box-folder 33/9)
  - Press releases, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 33/10)
  - Advertisements, 1940s (Box-folder 33/11)
  - Assorted catalogs, 1978-1979, and undated (Box-folder 33/12)
- Series 9. Epic Records, 1953-1956, .5 linear feet
  Primarily publicity material, including the publications News about Epic Records, Dateline Epic Classics, and Dateline Epic Pops.
  Arranged by publication title and chronologically within each publication.
  - Press department, 1954, 1956 (Box-folder 34/1)
  - News about Epic Records
    - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 34/2)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 34/3)
  - New Epic Record Label Releases, 1953 (Box-folder 34/4)
  - Dateline Epic Classics, 1956 (Box-folder 34/5)
  - Dateline Epic Pops, 1956 (Box-folder 34/6)
  - Other popular epicgram, classical epicgram, 1956 (Box-folder 34/7)
- Series 10. RCA Victor Records, 1941-1954, and undated, 2 linear feet
  The series includes publicity material and press department releases for RCA Victor Records, including individual series publications entitled News about RCA Victor Records, News Information, and Victor Record Bulletin.
  - News about RCA Victor Records
    - 1946 (Box-folder 35/1-2)
    - 1947 (Box-folder 35/3-4)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 35/5-8)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 36/1-4)
    - 1950, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 36-37, Box 36, Box 37)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 37/3-5)
    - 1952 (Box-folder 37/6)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 37/7-8)
    - undated (Box-folder 37/9-10)
  - RCA Communications, Inc., 1949 (Box-folder 38/1)
  - Announcing New Victor Red Seal Records
    - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 38/2)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 38/3-4)
    - undated (Box-folder 38/5)
  - News Information
    - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 38/6)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 38/7-8)
    - undated (Box-folder 38/9)
  - Victor Record Bulletin
    - 1945 (Box-folder 38/10-14)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 38/15)
  - Ephemera, 1940s, and 1954 (Box-folder 38/16)
  - Miscellaneous catalogs, undated (Box-folder 38/17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 38/18)
- Series 11. RCA Victor Argentina, 1947-1953, .5 linear feet
  Series includes publicity serial entitled Discos RCA Victor. Oversize material consists of accompanying promotional posters for individual record releases.
  - Discos RCA Victor
    - 1947 (Box-folder 39/1)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 39/2-3)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 39/4-7)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 39/8-9)
    - 1951-1952 (Box-folder 39/10)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 39/11-15)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 39/16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 39/17)
  - Promotional posters
    - 1950s (Box-folder OSC 1/2-5)
    - undated (Box-folder OSE 1/1)
  - Los Ultimos Exitos en Discos RCA Victor, 1950-1953 (Box-folder OSE 1/2)
  - Nuevos Discos RCA Victor, 1948-1950 (Oversize map case)
- Series 12. Independent Record Labels, 1937-1957, 1973, and undated, 1 linear foot
  Series 12 consists of promotional material from mail order record clubs such as American Recording Society, Concert Hall Society, Music Treasures of the World, and Disc of the Month; independent record labels such as Asch Records; overseas labels such as Columbia Graphophone Company; general record industry releases such as Vanguard News; market research material from Muzak Corporation and Copyright Office of Research, Inc.; and record retailers such as Steinway & Sons Record Shop and Gramophone Shop, Inc.
  Materials are arranged by company name.
  - American Recording Society, undated (Box-folder 40/1)
  - Asch Records/Folkways materials, 1945, and undated (Box-folder 40/2)
  - The Boston University Anthology of Recorded Music, 1957 (Box-folder 40/3)
  - Classophone, Inc., 1947 (Box-folder 40/4)
  - Columbia (EMI), 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 40/5)
  - Concert Hall Society, Inc., 1946, and undated (Box-folder 40/6)
  - Contemporary Records, Inc., 1953, and undated (Box-folder 40/7)
  - Copyright 1948, Office of Research, Inc., 1948 (Box-folder 40/8)
  - Disc of the Month, 1946 (Box-folder 40/9)
  - Enrichment Records, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 40/10)
  - Gramophone Shop, Inc., 1937, 1943, and undated (Box-folder 40/11)
  - Mercury, 1953, and undated (Box-folder 40/12)
  - Music Treasures of the World, 1957, and undated (Box-folder 40/13)
  - Muzak Corporation, 1946, and undated (Box-folder 40/14)
  - Steinway & Sons Record Shop, 1940s (Box-folder 40/15)
  - Vanguard News, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 40/16)
  - Phonograph equipment ads from various companies, 1940s (Box-folder 40/17)
  - Miscellaneous independent record label ephemera, 1939-1953, and undated (Box-folder 41/1)
  - Casa Bautista de Publicaciones, Catalogo Especial, 1973 (Box-folder 41/2)
  - Miscellaneous record industry press and media materials, 1948-1953, and undated (Box-folder 41/3)
  - Miscellaneous mail order record club fliers, 1940, 1947, and undated (Box-folder 41/4)
  - Miscellaneous non-English language ephemera, undated (Box-folder 41/5)
  - Miscellaneous record retailers, 1937, 1940, and undated (Box-folder 41/6)
  - Miscellaneous indices and catalogs, 1966, 1971, and 1976 (Box-folder 41/7)
- Series 13. Radio Companies, 1944-1946, and undated, .25 linear feet
  This series consists of press releases from the American Broadcasting Company (ABC) and scripts from various radio programs, such as Music of the Jazz Bands, Music of the Theatre, Outpost Concert Series, and Radio Symphonies of America.
  Materials are arranged according to program name.
  - Press releases for American Broadcasting Company (ABC) "serious music" radio and television programs, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 41/8)